誒。
多謝。
報導啊！介紹佢嗰個施政理念啦。
係一個整體嘅機器啦。呢個機器乜嘢咧？就係公務員嘅體係啦。
好，何君瑤議員嘅簡報會時段依家開始，會喺五點二十四分結束。好啊。
高興今日睇啊，聽到誒特首咧就喺二零二三年嘅施政報告裏邊作一個好詳細嘅。
誒，亦都係要點樣去弘揚中華文化呢一個咧，即係個本質個根啊，呢一個好重要嘅。
誒基本上我睇都係有三部分嘅。第一就係好強調咧，係誒國家嘅情懷，係國家安全啊呢個底線思維。
誒鼓勵我哋嘅誒社會裏邊個誒生育率啊，要提翻高啊，全部都係由一個係關愛嘅概念裏邊提出嚟。咁第三方面咧，就係。
同埋各方面嘅嗰個誒設立嘅誒吸金嘅委員會啦，因為我哋要講誒我哋嘅嗰個基金啊，大規模啊大型嘅發展需要呢個金融嘅融資啊。喺呢各各方面嘅嗰個機器機器方面嚟講咧。
誒對我哋誒香港嘅青年人咧，係有誒寄以厚望喺呢一方面教育咧，就國民嘅意識啊、誒身份認同咧，係誒比較偏重嘅。第二咧就係講呢個誒經濟方面嚟講咧，當然我哋香港係要喺。
喺呢一方面做得好啲。如果唔係，我哋點會有誒嗰個經濟嚟去支持其他嘅活動咧？咁所以裏邊頗為大嘅篇幅咧，都係講我哋點樣做好自己嘅誒本土嘅發展啦、經濟啦、誒無論你金融咧、誒喺誒科創啦，同埋。
誒喺誒誒有關誒解決民生嘅問題，誒居住同埋對各行各業同埋社會唔同嘅層層面裏裏邊咧，都有關愛嘅意念。譬如好似我哋講話嗰個商業上誒餐館噉啊，先畀。
發發牌後，再去去去去跟進佢嗰個誒規程啊，相關嘅嗰啲規定會唔會符合？我相信係係好人性化，即係第二部分咧。我就話咩咧？佢對整個社會，無論喺經濟方面嚟講，對我哋新人類啊、新生命誒。
係誒好關心，特別係公務員嘅誒工作嘅表現啦，啊要點樣提振啦，有賞有罰嚇，咁呢一個咧誒，我嚟去形容咧就公欲善其事，係必先利其器。喺呢一方面咧，特首係睇得到，亦都係要。
幾？
完成。
都未。
係國家所需而所所需要嘅時候，同時一定要確立得到高質量發展。
係叫做成功爭取嚇《基本法》二十三條咧，係一九九七年七月一號已經生效誒。
整合呢個成個橫切面推過去嘅時候，嗰個復原係好大，所以嗰個公欲善其事，必先利其器咧係好重要。噉啊，我我我睇到就係呢呢三樣嘢。嗱喺國內方面嚟講，特別有一個令我覺得終於係啊～
即係呢個國家安全法，淨係點理解呢個應當盡早完成咧？呢呢六個字咧，原來我哋香港都由二零二零年六月三十號去到今日嚇，係二零二三年十月二十五號，經過三年幾嘅時間咧。
嘅教育呢個要先正心，再修身，然後先可以齊到家啊治國嚟平天下。我諗呢啲唔係一個新鮮嘅思維，但係喺今次呢一個施政報告裏邊係充分體現出嚟。我今日同大家講係咁多啦。OK，有冇其他問題？
揸緊嚟做，無論喺嗰個開源節流方面嚟講嘅嗰個基礎配套設施咧，佢都要諗到。咁所以今次呢一個誒二零二三年嘅施政報告比以往咧都仲嚟得重咗，就係誒係喺嗰個融資方面誒支配我哋香港有好多大型嘅機。
誒由呢一個誒大嶼山北部人工島去到呢一個北部都會，甚至乎由西至東噉樣個橫跨性嘅嗰個寬度好大，係河套啊，一路去新田啊、落馬洲同埋去到呢一個沙頭角咧，同內地裏邊要點樣？
國家安全嘅呢條法例咧，應該係按二十三條裏邊咧，係要盡早去落實執行。咁但係我哋好事多磨，過去由一九九七年去到二零零三年，突然之間咧就係被被人慣咗一鋪嚇，咁然後跟住二二零二零二零零三年之後一路。
度都冇任何動靜，個個都話要分為分為，最後就係個個都分迷咗啊！冇做到任何嘢噉啊。終於喺二零一九年，我哋大家都畀黑暴事件咧係震醒咗，醒咗之後噉，究竟要點樣完善好佢咧？國家終於出手，就喺二零二零年嘅六月三十號咧。
港區維護國家安全法咧，係短短五個星期裏邊由兩會通過拍板，然後去到六月三十號子夜去實施咧，前後唔過五個禮拜，呢個叫國家速度。喺當中裏邊，今日特首亦都已經有講到第七條啊，就話啦，特區政府應當盡早完成立法嘅。
仲而家我哋講啊，雖然係遲，但係亦都係值得慶幸喺二零二四年裏邊咧，係會完成咗呢一個誒二十三條立法。即係前後夾埋咧，要花成四年幾五年嚟去體體驗咗，就嗰個叫做應當盡早完成啦。咁嗱，呢一個咧就我覺得係誒。
應該係係一個好嘅，始終都係一個好嘅發展。誒，亦都係誒誒遲到好過冇到，雖然唔係好早到。咁但係我我覺得誒，就住香港整體環境嚟講咧，誒國家係仍仍然認為香港嘅所長。
請。
第二。
encouraging young couple to give birth to to to to children.
flare up the issue for everybody to have the heads up. Okay, this is how I see it.
Would it be better use otherwise? I don't see. I don't see much difference. In fact, you know, the figure itself is.
If the money not spend for this purpose, okay, and and would it be better use? I think you know, twenty thousand for
take up the responsibility to raise a child， you know， not just up to eighteen， you know， even way beyond eighteen， up， even up to thirty。
They, as far as I can see, there are two major reasons. Number one, being parents is is not easy at all. You have to
to give birth to a young baby, so we're talking about giving twenty thousand for forty couples, so it's minimal amount of money. So if not spend for
人才都係一樣要高質量發展，唔單止佢讀得到精算啊，或者咩都好。但係如果個思想個心係唔正的話咧，你讀得更多書都好咧，冇鬼用係嘛？咁所以咧就喺呢個開章裏邊咧，即係開宗明義第一章裏邊講，要搞好呢一個誒愛國者。
No problem. Fire, fire, fire your question. Okay. I'd like to get your thoughts on the twenty thousand one time cash bonus to incentivise parents to have kids, families to have kids. Do you think that this will really be effective in encouraging families to have children, or do you think twenty thousand is way too little money?
Or do you maybe think that by trying to use money to solve the problem, that it perhaps might be neglecting other reasons why families do not want to have children in Hong Kong? Well, you have raised a very good question. Actually, the first first question, first part of your question, to ask whether or not twenty zero would be
Enough. Well, there would never be. It would never be enough. Okay, but at least it is. It's better than nothing. It serve as some kind of incentive and encouragement. And and also signified one problem that we are now facing. Aging. Okay, the society is aging. We are getting older and older by.
By two thousand and thirty, there will be one third of our population will exceed the age of sixty. So that is not a a light question and and is a very serious problem that the government should address the attention to. So I think you know twenty thousand is to.
Let's look at the figure. You know, the existing birth rate is only 0.9% of the population. That means it's less, a little bit less than 80,000. So if you just time this, you know, it takes two to to to make up a family, a couple to have to nurture a family and to to to to raise.
It's a little bit minimal. Okay, it doesn't serve any other so-called the purpose or waste wasteage purpose at all. Number three, what is the reason why the younger generation doesn't want to have family and doesn't want to have babies? Well, exactly, you know, this is the problem.
years old, you still have to look after them nowadays. is is a phenomenal, is common common common feature. and second, why is this so? Well, well, as I said, it is such a grave responsibility, land on the shoulder of the young couple. So therefore, it scare them off. You know, this maybe.
你 never know what you're going to get, so therefore.
Mind you, it's not a a one plus one is equal to two strict formula to suggest that.
probably， you know， this is the reason also which deter younger generation to raise the family and to to bear birth of young child。好，唔該曬咁多位，呢一次時間完結啦，多謝。
One of the reasons, the second one is that you know the younger generation wouldn't want to would want to enjoy life more than our older generations. Our older generations would like to endure the life whatever it takes to raise our second generation.
older generation would would love to commit that would love to make that sort of commitment and to to go through that sort of the self self sacrificing self self sacrifice path whether or not the young couple young young generation would like
to to repeat that path that our older generation had gone through, I know not. is is very much a question that you may answer yourself. But I myself, being a a father of three, I also have to, I also had to go through this sort of.
the responsibility and overcome all the problems along the way. Not just financially, it is a burden. Educationally, teaching, you know, raising them, you have to sacrifice a lot in terms of your private time and also and and energy efforts.
given your hard work and and great you know great input into into it, it means the answer must be positive. No, life is is is is is is a tempting fate. It's just like a you know as as Forrest Gump mother said you know a box of chocolate.